William H. Ryder Collection of Confederate History MS011
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Cartes de Visite - Photographs, 1770 -- 1890; MS011.001; 1.45 Linear Feet; 180 Digital Object(s)
  - Dr. Artom [Rev. Dr. Benjamin], 1873 -- 1879; MS011.001.001.00059; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Rev. Dr. Benjamin Artom; Chief Rabbi of the Spanish and Portugese Jews' congregations in England; died Jan. 6 1879; aged 45 years." Clipping from newspaper article pasted on back of card. Produced by: The London Stereoscopic & Photographic Company. 110 & 108, Regent Street and 54, Cheapside.
    Judaism; cartes-de-visite; Artom, Benjamin, 1835-1879
  - Immanuel Kant, 1780 -- 1804; MS011.001.001.00060; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Immanuel Kant; Geb. 22 April 1724 zu Konigsberg, gest 12. Febr. 1804. (Born April 22, 1724 in Konigsberg, died Febr. 12 1804.)" Produced by: Gustav Schauer, Photographisches Kunst un Verlags- Institut, Berlin, Grosse Friedrichs-Strasse 188. These dates are approximate and refer to the painting, not the carte-de-visite.
    Philosophers; cartes-de-visite; Kant, Immanuel, 1724-1804
  - H. R. H. [His Royal Highness] the Prince of Wales [Prince Albert Edward, Edward VII], 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00061; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: London Stereoscopic Comp., 54 Cheapside.
    Kings (people); Princes; cartes-de-visite; Edward VII, King of Great Britain, 1841-1910
  - Poesie, 1875 -- 1885; MS011.001.001.00062; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Les grands poetes contemporains [The great contemporary poets]; Lamartine; Alfred de Musset; Victor Hugo." Produced by: Paris Atelier Phot. de A. Jordan [?], R. Villedo, 10.
    Poets; cartes-de-visite; Lamartine, Alphonse de, 1790-1869; Musset, Alfred de, 1810-1857; Hugo, Victor, 1802-1885
  - Prof. Petermann [August], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00063; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. Petermann." Produced by A. Linde, Hof-Photograph, Gotha, August Straße 3.
    cartes-de-visite; Petermann, A. (August), 1822-1878
  - Prof. Charles Beck, 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00064; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. Charles Beck." Produced by Whipple, 207 Washington Street, Boston.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite; Beck, Charles, 1798-1866
  - Boss Tweed [William "Boss" Tweed], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00065; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Boss Tweed." Produced by: Gurney, Fifth Avenue, Cor. 16th St, N.Y.
    Politicians; cartes-de-visite; Tweed, William Marcy, 1823-1878
  - Prof. Ed. [Johann Eduard] Erdmann, 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00066; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Photograph., Atelier von Anders-Paltzow Portraitmaler, Galle a. S., grosse Ulrichstr. 35.
  - Gen. Blenker [Louis], 1861 -- 1863; MS011.001.001.00067; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find pict of; Gen'l Blenker; General Louis Blenker; Union General 1812-63; Germany."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Blenker, Louis, 1812-1863
  - Com. Foote [Andrew Hull], 1861 -- 1863; MS011.001.001.00068; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Foote, Andrew Hull 1806-1863; Rear Admiral July 16, 1862; (rear admiral)."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Foote, Andrew H. (Andrew Hull), 1806-1863
  - Commodore Du Pont [Samuel Francis], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00069; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find pict of; Com Du Pont; Samuel Francis Du Pont; Union Admiral 1803-65; New Jersey." Produced by: E. Anthony, 501 Broadway, New York.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Du Pont, Samuel Francis, 1803-1865
  - McClellan, George Brinton, 1862; MS011.001.001.00070; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "McClellan, George Brinton 1826-1885; General-in-Chief (Union Army) 1861-1862; Major General (reg. army) May 1861-Nov. 1861; March 1862-1864." Produced by: Silsbee, Case & Co. Photographic Artists, 299 1/2 Washington Street, Boston.
  - Gen. Buell [Don Carlos], 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00071; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "find pict. of; Don Carlo Buell; Union General 1818-1898; Ohio."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Buell, Don Carlos, 1818-1898
  - Gen. McDowell [Irvin], 1861; MS011.001.001.00072; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "McDowell, Irvin 1818-1885; Major-gen'l (Union) March 1862-1864." Produced by D. Appleton & Co.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; McDowell, Irvin, 1818-1885
  - Gen. Scott [Winfield], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00073; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Scott, Winfield 1786-1866; General in Chief (Union Army) June 1841- Nov. 1, 1861."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Scott, Winfield, 1786-1866
  - Union Generals, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00074; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Union Generals; Maj.-General McClellan; Brig.-General Anderson; Maj.-General Fremont; Maj.-General Butler; Maj.-General Dix."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; McClellan, George Brinton, 1826-1885; Anderson, Robert, 1805-1871; Frmont, John Charles, 1813-1890; Butler, Benjamin F. (Benjamin Franklin), 1818-1893.; Dix, John Adams, 1798-1879
  - Brig. Gen. Robt [Robert] Anderson, 1861; MS011.001.001.00075; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Anderson, Robert 1805-1871; Brigadier General; Union Army May 15, 1861-1863." Produced by: D. Appleton and Co.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Anderson, Robert, 1805-1871
  - General Winfield Scott, 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00076; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "General Winfield Scott 1786-1866; General -in-Chief (Union Army) June 1841-Nov. 1, 1861."
  - Gen. Grant [Ulysses] of Fort Donelson, 1861 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00077; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Grant; Grant, Ulysses Simpson 1822-1885; General-in-Chief (Union Army) 1864-; President of the U.S. 1868-77." Produced by: Snyder, Black & Sturn, N.Y.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Grant, Ulysses S. (Ulysses Simpson)
  - Chase, Salmon Portland, 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00078; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Chase; Chase, Salmon Portland 1808-1873; Sec. Treasury, U.S.A. March 5, 1861- June 30, 1864; Chief Justice of U.S. Dec. 15, 1864-1873." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    Politicians; cartes-de-visite; Chase, Salmon P. (Salmon Portland), 1808-1873
  - Fransecky [Eduard Friedrich Karl von], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00079; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; cartes-de-visite; Fransecky, Eduard Friedrich von, 1807-1890
  - Grant, Ulysses Simpson, 1861 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00081; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Grant; Grant, Ulysses Simpson 1822-1885; Union General-in-Chief 1864-; President of the U.S. 1868- 1877." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
  - [Woman with hair down], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00082; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Allen & Horton, Photographers, No. 13 Winter Street, Boston.
    Woman; cartes-de-visite
  - [Woman with bow in hair], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00083; Unknown (Box 1)
  - [Woman with hat], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00084; Unknown (Box 1)
  - Tennyson [Lord Alfred], 1861; MS011.001.001.00086; Unknown (Box 1)
    "Tennyson." Produced by: London Stereoscopic Comp. 54 Cheapside (2 Doors from Bow Church): Under the Patronage of Her Majesty.
    cartes-de-visite; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron
  - Beyer [Gustav Friedrich von], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00087; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Beyer, Gustav Friedrich von, 1812-1889
  - A. Ewald [?], 1867; MS011.001.001.00088; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "A. Ewald; Gottinger Marz 1867." Produced by: G. Markwort, Steinstrasse No. 9, Darmstadt.
  - Failly [?], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00089; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. The person pictured does not match other pictures of French General Pierre Louis Charles de Failly and is probably incorrectly identified. Identity remains unknown but is probably a French General.
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Failly, Pierre Louis Charles Achille de, 1810-1892
  - Kirchbach [Hugo Ewald Graf von], 1870 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00090; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Carte de visite photographs; cartes-de-visite; Kirchbach, Hugo Ewald Graf von, 1809-1887
  - [Three men in hats], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00091; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Negretti & Zambra, Photographers to the Crystal Palace, Sydenham.
    People; cartes-de-visite
  - Thiers [Adolphe], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00092; Unknown (Box 1)
    Politicians; cartes-de-visite; Thiers, Adolphe, 1797-1877
  - Bose [Julius von], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00093; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Bose, Julius von, 1809-1894
  - König von Bayern [Ludwig II of Bavaria], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00094; Unknown (Box 1)
    Kings and rulers; cartes-de-visite; Ludwig II, King of Bavaria, 1845-1886
  - Souvenir de Pelerinage de Notre Dame de Fourvieres [statue], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00095; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: J. G. Gadola, Èditeur, 2, Cours de Brosses, 2, Lyon.
    Statues; image/tiff
  - [Waterfront building with four industrial sized chimneys on roof and a boat in front], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00096; Unknown (Box 1)
    Buildings; cartes-de-visite
  - King of Prussia [Wilhelm I (William I)], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00097; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "King of Prussia."
    Emperors; cartes-de-visite; William I, German Emperor, 1797-1888
  - Admiral Jachmann [Eduard von], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00098; Unknown (Box 1)
    cartes-de-visite; Jachmann, Eduard von, 1822-1887
  - Leopold von Hohenzollern, 1870 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00099; Unknown (Box 1)
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Hohenzollern, Leopold, F&#00FC;rst von, 1835-1905
  - Kaiserliche Prinz (Imperial Prince) [Napoleon IV], 1859 -- 1863; MS011.001.001.00100; Unknown (Box 1)
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Louis Napoleon, Prince Imperial of the French, 1856-1879
  - Bazaine [Françoise Achille], 1860 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00101; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Bazaine, François-Achille, 1811-1888
  - Ollivier [Èmile], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00102; Unknown (Box 1)
    Politicians; Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Ollivier, Emile, 1825-1913
  - Fürst Pleß [Count Pless, Hans Heinrich XI], 1870 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00103; Unknown (Box 1)
    cartes-de-visite; Fürst Pleß, Hans Heinrich XI
  - Coffinieres [Grégoire Gaspard Félix], 1860 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00104; Unknown (Box 1)
    2.5 X 4.25.
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Coffinières, Gré Gaspard Fé1811-1887
  - Gramont [Antoine Alfred Agénor, duc de], 1855 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00105; Unknown (Box 1)
    Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Gramont, Antoine Alfred Agéuc de, 1819-1880
  - Gov. Andrew [John Albion], 1860 -- 1867; MS011.001.001.00106; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Gov. Andrew." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    Governors; Politicians; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Andrew, John A. (John Albion), 1818-1867
  - Stiehle [Gustav von], 1870 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00107; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Stiehle, Gustav von, 1823-1899
  - Leboeuf [Edmond], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00108; Unknown (Box 1)
    cartes-de-visite; Leboeuf, Edmond, 1809-1888
  - Kameke [Georg von], 1870 -- 1871; MS011.001.001.00109; Unknown (Box 1)
    Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Kameke, Georg von, 1817-1893
  - Falckenstein [Eduard Vogel von], 1865 -- 1873; MS011.001.001.00110; Unknown (Box 1)
    Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Falckenstein, Eduard Vogel von, 1797-1885
  - Goeben [August Karl von], 1860 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00111; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Goeben, August von, 1816-1880
  - Kameke [?], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00112 (Box 1)
    25. The person pictured does not match other pictures of General Georg von Kameke and is probably incorrectly identified. Identity remains unknown.
    Generals; cartes-de-visite; Kameke, Georg von, 1817-1893
  - Planksy [?], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00113; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Person pictured remains unidentified, handwriting appears to read, "Plansky."
    Man; cartes-de-visite
  - Sherman, Wlm. [William] Tecumseh, 1860 -- 1865; MS011.001.001.00114; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Sherman, Wlm. Tecumseh 1820-1891; Major General (Union Reg. Army) Aug. 12, 1864- ." Produced by: Joseph Ward, 125 Washington Street, Boston.
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Sherman, William T. (William Tecumseh), 1820-1891
  - King of Prussia [Wilhelm I], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00115; Unknown (Box 1)
  - Young America, 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00116; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Young America." Produced by: S. Kingman, 28 1-2 Winter St., Boston.
    Boys; cartes-de-visite
  - Ellsworth [Elmer Ephraim], 1860 -- 1861; MS011.001.001.00117; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Ellsworth, Elmer Ephraim 1837-1861; no rank given."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; cartes-de-visite; Ellsworth, Elmer
  - Gen. Heintzelman [Samuel Peter], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00118; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Gen. Heintzelman; Heintzelman, Samuel Peter; Union General 1805-1880."
    United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Heintzelman, Samuel Peter, 1805-1880
  - Prinz Frederick Chs. [Prince Frederick Charles], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00119; Unknown (Box 1)
    "Prinz Frederick Chs."
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Frederick Charles, Prince of Prussia, 1828-1885
  - Bismarck [Otto von], 1865 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00120; Unknown (Box 1)
    Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Bismarck, Otto, F&#00FC;rst von, 1815-1898
  - Napoleon III, 1863 -- 1873; MS011.001.001.00121; Unknown (Box 1)
    Emperors; cartes-de-visite; Napoleon III, Emperor of the French, 1808-1873
  - Prinz August von Wörttemberg, 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00122; Unknown (Box 1)
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Friedrich August Eberhard, Prinz von Wörttemberg
  - Kronprinz [Friedrich Wilhelm Nikolaus Karl, Friedrich III], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00123; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Kronprinz."
    Princes; cartes-de-visite; Frederick III, German Emperor, 1831-1888
  - Kronprinz von Sachsen [Albert of Saxony], 1865 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00124; Unknown (Box 1)
    Kings (people); cartes-de-visite; Albert, King of Saxony, 1828-1902
  - Zastrow [Alexander Friedrich Adolf Heinrich von], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00125; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Zastrow, Heinrich Adolf von, 1801-1875
  - Podbielski [Eugen Anton Theophil von], 1870 -- 1879; MS011.001.001.00126; Unknown (Box 1)
    Generals; cartes-de-visite; Podbielski, Eugen Anton Theophil von, 1814-1879
  - Bismarck [Otto von], Roon [Albrecht von], Moltke [Helmuth von], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00127; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Bismarck; Roon; Moltke."
    Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Bismarck, Otto, F&#00FC;rst von, 1815-1898; Roon, Albrecht, Graf von, 1803-1879; Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891
  - Gen. Moltke [Helmuth Karl Bernhard Graf von], 1875 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00128; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Gen. Moltke."
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Moltke, Helmuth, Graf von, 1800-1891
  - King of Prußia [King of Prussia, Wilhelm I], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00129; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "King of Prußia."
    Kings (people); image/tiff; William I, German Emperor, 1797-1888
  - Manstein [Albrecht Gustav von], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00130; Unknown (Box 1)
    Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; image/tiff; Manstein, Albrecht Gustav von, 1805-1877
  - Frossard [Charles Auguste], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00132; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Frossard, Charles Auguste, 1807-1875
  - Tümpling [Wilhelm von], 1860 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00133; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Tümpling, Wilhelm von, 1809-1884
  - Prof. H. Oort [Professor Hans van Oort], 1780 -- 1876; MS011.001.001.00134; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Oort. Prof. H. Oort." Produced by: A. Koorenhoff, artiste, photograph, Leiden, Muskadelsteeg No. 5, by de Pieterskerk.
    Professors; cartes-de-visite
  - The Rt. Rev. The Lord Bishop of Natal: Dr. Colenso [John William], 1873 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00135; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Clipping from newspaper article pasted on back of card. Produced by: The London Stereoscopic & Photographic Company. 110 & 108, Regent Street and 54, Cheapside.
    Bishops (prelates); cartes-de-visite; Colenso, John William, 1814-1883
  - Franz Delitzsch, 1865 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00136; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Franz Delitzsch." Produced by: Photograph, artistilsche, Anstalt von August Brasch, Leipzig, Linden-Strasse No. 7.
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Delitzsch, Franz, 1813-1890
  - M. de Cavour [Camillo Paolo Filippo Giulio Benso, Count of Cavour], 1865 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00137; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Mayer & Pierson, photographes de S.M. L'Empereur, Bolevart des Capucines, 3, Paris.
    Counts; cartes-de-visite; Cavour, Camillo Benso, conte di, 1810-1861
  - Schenkel [Georg Daniel], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00138; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Produced by: Photographische Anstalt, Ed. Lange, Heidelberg, Westliche Hauptstrasse, No. 81.
    Professors; Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Schenkel, Daniel, 1813-1885
  - Prof. Baur [Ferdinand Christian], 1855 -- 1860; MS011.001.001.00139; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Prof. Baur; (T&#00FC;bingen)." Produced by: F. Brandseph, Photograph Anstals, Stuttgart.
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Baur, Ferdinand Christian, 1792-1860
  - Kuenen [Abraham], 1860 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00140; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Kuenen." Produced by: Photographie von A. Koorenhoff, Muskadelsteeg No. 634 te Leiden.
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Kuenen, Abraham, 1828-1891
  - David Strauß [Strauss], 1865 -- 1874; MS011.001.001.00141; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "David Strauß." Produced by: Hof-Photograph Hermann Günther früher Werderscher Markt No. 6, jezt [sic; now]: Ziethenplatz No. 2, Berlin.
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Strauss, David Friedrich, 1808-1874
  - Carl Ritter, 1855 -- 1859; MS011.001.001.00142; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Carl Ritter." Produced by: Eigenthum und Verlag von E. H. Schroeder, Hermann Kaiser, Berlin, 41. Unter den Linden 41.
    cartes-de-visite; Ritter, Carl, 1779-1859
  - Barnekov [?] [Laurent Soubrane?], 1865 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00143; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. The handwriting identifying the person pictured is difficult to read, it may say "Barnekov." The image might depict Barnekov, Laurent Soubrane.
    Generals; cartes-de-visite; Barnekov, Laurent Soubrane
  - Hermann Schulz [sic, Shulze?], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00144; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Herman Schulz. Schults." Produced by: Photographie von Bernh. Petri in G&#00F6;ttingen, Weender-Strasse 80.
    cartes-de-visite; Schulze, Hermann J. F. (Hermann Johann Friedrich), 1824-1888
  - Pietrowsky, Die Fuchstauf [Baptisme of the fox], 1855 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00145; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Pietrowsky; Die Fuchstauf 346; Le bapt&#00CA;me du renard; The Initiation." Maximilian Anton Piotrowski was a painter from Germany. Produced by: Gustav Schauer, Photographisches Kunst und Verlages- Institut, Berlin, Gross Friedrichs-Strasse 188.
    Paintings; cartes-de-visite; Piotrowski, Maximilian Anton
  - The only true likeness of Our Saviour, 1867; MS011.001.001.00146; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. Extract from P&#00FC;blius Lentulus' description of Jesus Christ is printed on back. Produced by: Sperry Bros. This date is approximate and refers to the photograph, not the etching.
    Portraits; cartes-de-visite; Jesus Christ
  - Friedrich Schleiermacher, 1818 -- 1838; MS011.001.001.00147; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Friedrich Schleiermacher." Produced by: Eigenthum und Verlag von E. H. Schroeder, Hermann Kaiser, Berlin, 41. Unter den Linden 41. These dates are approximate and refer to the painting, not the carte-de-visite
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Schleiermacher, Friedrich, 1768-1834
  - Famille Impériale [Imperial Family], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00148; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Famille Impériale." Produced by: Disdéri, Photographes de S. M. L'empereur, 8 Boulevart des Italiens, Paris.
    cartes-de-visite
  - Moses Mendelssohn, 1770 -- 1786; MS011.001.001.00149; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Moses Mendelssohn." Produced by: Eigenthum und Verlag von E. H. Schroeder, Hermann Kaiser, Berlin, 41. Unter den Linden 41. These dates are approximate and refer to the painting, not the carte-de-visite.
    Philosophers; cartes-de-visite; Mendelssohn, Moses, 1729-1786
  - Renan [Ernest], 1869; MS011.001.001.00150; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Renan." Produced by: Erwin, Hanfstaengl, Photographe de La M. le roi de Prusse, 4, Rue Frochot, 4, en face la Rue Breda, Paris.
    Philosophers; cartes-de-visite; Renan, Ernest, 1823-1892
  - Scholten [Jan Hendrik], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00151; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Scholten; Scholten."
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Scholten, Jan Hendrik, 1811-1885
  - Emperor [Napoleon III], 1865 -- 1873; MS011.001.001.00152; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Napoleon III." Produced by: Disderi & C. Photographes de S. M. L'empereur, 8 Boulevart des Italiens, Paris.
  - Stülpnagel [Wolf Louis Anton Ferdinand von], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00153; Unknown (Box 1)
    Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Stülpnagel, Wolf Louis Anton Ferdinand von, 1813-1885
  - Alvensleben II [Reimar Constantin von], 1860 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00154; Unknown (Box 1)
    Austro-Prussian War, 1866; Franco-Prussian War, 1870-1871; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Alvensleben, Constantin i.e. Reimar Constantin von, 1809-1892
  - Mac Mahon [Patrice de Mac-Mahon], 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00155; Unknown (Box 1)
    Counts; Politicians; Generals; cartes-de-visite; Mac-Mahon, Edme Patrice Maurice, comte de, 1808-1893
  - Béranger [Pierre-Jean de], 1855 -- 1857; MS011.001.001.00156; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "B&#00E9;ranger." Produced by: E. Desmaisons, 5, Rue des Grands Augustins, Paris.
    Poets; cartes-de-visite; Béranger, Pierre Jean de, 1780-1857
  - H. [Heinrich] Kiepert, 1870 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00157; Unknown (Box 1)
    "H. Kiepert; (Geographer)." Produced by: Oscar Roloff, hof-Photograph, Berlin, Oranienstrasse 81 u. 82.
    cartes-de-visite; Kiepert, Heinrich, 1818-1899
  - Ricasoli [Bettino], 1860 -- 1870; MS011.001.001.00158; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Ricasoli." Produced by: Duroni & Murer, Opticiens Photographes de S. M. Le Roi D'Italie, Paris, 12, Rue Vivienne, Milan, 11, Corso Vitt. Emanuel.
    Statesmen; cartes-de-visite; Ricasoli, Bettino, 1809-1880
  - Schenkel [Georg Daniel], 1865 -- 1875; MS011.001.001.00159; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Schenkel." Produced by: Photographische Anstalt, Ed. Lange, Heidelberg, Westliche Hauptstrasse, No. 81.
    Theologians; cartes-de-visite; Schenkel, Daniel, 1813-1885
  - Annie Louise Cary, 1868 -- 1878; MS011.001.001.00160; Unknown (Box 1)
    25. "Miss Carey; Couhalts." Produced by: Sarony & Co., Photographers, 680 Broadway, N.Y., Napoleon Sarony, Alfred S. Camprell.
    Singers; cartes-de-visite; Cary, Annie Louise, 1842-1921
  - Wilson, 1865 -- 1880; MS011.001.001.00161; Unknown (Box 1)